## **Hakan Tek**

Universitätsstraße 7, 33615 Bielefeld

☐ hakan.tek@stud.th-owl.de | ☐ +49 1573 5687740 | ☐ hakanttek

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

An engineer who likes to develop algorithms and software. Developed projects with teammates in the fields of operation research and deep learning, resulting in a TUBITAK award. A paragliding pilot who likes to fly with the student club. A Lieferando biker who loves mountain biking.



#### **EDUCATION**

2020 – Present Production Engineering and Management, M.Sc.,

Technische Hochschule Ostwestfalen-Lippe, Lemgo, Germany

University of Trieste (Double degree), Pordenone, Italy

2014 – 2019 Industrial Engineering, B.Sc.,

Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey (3.09)

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

Jan – Sep 2020 R&D Engineer (Full time) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Developed an open-source ERP software for production planning and

control. See project here: github.com/AkarTextile/erp4j.git

Apr – Dec 2019 Production Engineer (Full time) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Formulated the standard times in Cutting Department and determinate the

operators' performances.

Nov 2018 – Jun 2019 Project Engineering (Intern) / Philip Morris International, Izmir, Turkey

Within the scope of the university graduation project, developed the number of defective products prediction model using machine learning algorithms.

See project here: github.com/hakanttek/SeniorProject.git

Nov 2018 – Feb 2019 Assistant Teacher (Part time) / Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey

Provided training for Excel to the students and the beginner staffs in Teaching and Learning Center. Developed an Excel macro for item analysis.

Aug – Sep 2018 System Engineer (Intern) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Wrote a macro which optimally assigning the product models to the lines

using Excel, VBA and Solver.

Jun – Aug 2018 Production Engineer (Intern) / Hugo Boss, ESBAŞ, Izmir, Turkey

Got training about production engineering and personal growth. Wrote a macro for optimally machine layout planning using Excel, VBA and solver.

Jul – Sep 2017 Production Control Engineer (Intern) / Delphi Technologies, Izmir, Turkey

Did an internship in the tugger system project.

**VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE** 

Sep 2021 – Present Buddy Student / TH-OWL, Lemgo, Germany

Helping two incoming students to adapt to Germany.

Oct 2017 – Oct 2018 Chairperson / IUE Aviation Club, Izmir, Turkey

Launch the autonomous uav project. Paragliding trainings were organized.

May – Sep 2016 Fundraiser / UNICEF, Izmir, Turkey

Persuaded the people, who walk on the street, into being a supporter.

### **Hakan Tek**

# Universitätsstraße 7, 33615 Bielefeld ☐ hakan.tek@stud.th-owl.de | ☐ +49 1573 5687740 | ☐ hakanttek

**SKILLS** 

Vocational IBM ILOG CPLEX Optimization Studio (Advanced), Excel & VBA (Advanced),

EDS(Intermediate), SAP S/4 HANA (Beginner), Teamcenter (Beginner)

Programming Java (Advanced), Python (Intermediate), C# (Intermediate),

SQL (Intermediate), HTML & CSS (Beginner)

Language Turkish (Native), English (Advanced), German (Intermediate)

**ACHIEVEMENT** 

Sep 2020 Encouragement Award – Akar Textile R&D Center

June 2019 Aegean Region Winner – TÜBİTAK 2242 Undergraduate Students Research

**Project Competition** 

June 2019 Paper Acceptance – 39<sup>th</sup> Operations Research / Industrial Engineering

**National Congress** 

**CERTIFICATES** 

June 2019 39<sup>th</sup> Operations Research / Industrial Engineering National Congress –

Başkent University (3 Days)

Sep 2019 Teknofest – Republic of Turkey Ministry of Industrial (5 Days)

June 2018 Create Your Future, Design Thinking and Formation Future Vision Workshop

Hugo Boss (13 Hours)

June – July 2018 Object-oriented programming C# – Elginkan Foundation (80 Hours)

Mar 2018 12<sup>nd</sup> MÜYAK – Anadolu University (3 Days)

Feb 2018 IndEx'18 – Koç University (3 Days)

Sep – Oct 2017 Advanced Excel Course – Elginkan Foundation (56 Hours)

Sep 2017 – Jan 2018 Kaizen, 5S Principles, Benchmarking and 6 Sigma Seminars – Elginkan

Foundation (16 Hours)

Jan 2017 24<sup>th</sup> ITU EMÖS – Istanbul Technical University (5 Days)

Mar 2016 Zirve'16 – Yaşar University (4 Hours)

**HOBBIES** 

Mountain biking, paragliding, swimming, escape game, crime fiction and science fiction.

**REFERENCES** 

Metin Üyük Electronics Team Supervisor / Philip Morris International, Izmir, Turkey

Office Phone: +90 (232) 488 73 24 Email: Metin.Uyuk@pmi.com

Asst. Prof. G. Reşat Academician / Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey

Office Phone: +90 (232) 488 84 65 Email: giray.resat@ieu.edu.tr

Hakan Sarper Production Engineer / Hugo Boss, ESBAŞ, Izmir, Turkey

Mobile: +90 533 331 31 13 Email: Hakan\_Sarper@hugoboss.com